Finding Aid for the Bob Brown Papers LSC.0723
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bob Brown papers
1844-1960
UCLA Library Special Collections
Brown, Bob
LSC.0723
45.2 linear feet (112 boxes and 1 flat box)
Bob Brown (1886-1959) was a writer, editor, publisher, and traveler. The collection consists of personal papers, manuscripts (including examples of Brown's visual/conceptual writings), publications, correspondence, photographs, cookbooks and other gastronomic-related items, clippings, and miscellaneous ephemera.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Eleanor Parker Brown, 1961.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942304203606533
Biography
Robert Carlton Brown (1886-1959) was a writer, editor, publisher, and traveler. From 1908 to 1917, he wrote poetry and prose for numerous magazines and newspapers in New York City, publishing two pulp novels, What Happened to Mary and The Remarkable Adventures of Christopher Poe (1913), and one volume of poetry, My Marjonary (1916).
During 1918, he traveled extensively in Mexico and Central America, writing for the U.S. Committee of Public Information in Santiago de Chile. In 1919, he moved with his wife, Rose Brown, to Rio de Janeiro, where they founded Brazilian American, a weekly magazine that ran until 1929. With Brown's mother, Cora, the Browns also established magazines in Mexico City and London: Mexican American (1924-1929) and British American (1926-1929).
Following the stock market crash of 1929, the Browns retired from publishing and traveled through Asia and Europe, settling in France from 1929-1933. Brown became involved in the expatriate literary community in Paris, publishing several volumes of poetry, including Globe Gliding (1930), Gems (1931), Words (1931), and Demonics (1931), as well as 1450-1950 (1929), a book of visual poetry. While in France, Brown also made plans toward, and wrote a manifesto for, the development of a "reading machine" involving the magnified projection of miniaturized type printed on movable spools of tape. Arguing that such a device would enable literature to compete with cinema in a visual age, Brown published a book of "Readies"---poems by Gertrude Stein, Fillipo Marinetti, William Carlos Williams, Ezra Pound, and others, typeset in a manner appropriate to operation of his projected reading machine. Although Brown's reading machine was never developed, his papers include letters and papers pertaining to its projected design and technical specifications, as well as a collection of his own published and unpublished visual and conceptual writing.
In 1933, Brown returned to New York. In the 1930s, he wrote a series of international cookbooks in collaboration with Rose and Cora Brown. He also lived in cooperative colonies in Arkansas and Louisiana, visited the USSR, and wrote a book, Can We Co-Operate (1940), regarding the parameters of a viable American socialism. In 1941, he and Rose returned to South America. While traveling down the Amazon they amassed a substantial collection of art and cultural artifacts and collaborated on a book, Amazing Amazon (1942). The Browns eventually reestablished residence in Rio de Janeiro, where they lived until Rose Brown's death in 1952. Following his wife's death, Bob Brown returned to New York, where he married Eleanor Parker in 1953. Brown continued to write and ran a shop called Bob Brown's Books in Greenwich Village until his death in 1959. Shortly after Brown's death, a new edition of 1450-1950 was published by Jonathan Williams's Jargon/Corinth Press.
Scope and Content
This collection documents the activities of Bob Brown (1886-1959)--writer, editor, publisher, and traveler. The collection documents various aspects of his personal and professional life and consists of personal papers, manuscripts (including examples of Brown's visual/conceptual writings), publications, correspondence, photographs, cookbooks and other gastronomic-related items, clippings, and miscellaneous ephemera.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Bob Brown papers (22 items).
Publishers and publishing -- Archives.; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Brown, Bob, 1886-1959--Archives.
- 14 poets, 1 artist... Jargon 31. (Box 1)
- A salute to all [out to Bob Brown April 8, 1958]. (Box 1)
- Berkeley (2 issues) and Contempo (2 issues). (Box 1)
- Bibliography. (Box 1)
- Correspondence. (Box 1)
- Correspondence -- Bern Porter. (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Betty Rosenberg. (Box 1)
- Demonics [missing October 7, 1982]. (Box 1)
- Gastronomy material. (Box 1)
- Material on Brazil. (Box 1)
- Poet's life [missing October 7, 1982]. (Box 1)
- [Red folder] (folder 1 of 6). (Box 2)
- [Red folder] (folder 2 of 6). (Box 2)
- [Red folder] (folder 3 of 6). (Box 2)
- [Red folder] (folder 4 of 6). (Box 2)
- [Red folder] (folder 5 of 6). (Box 2)
- [Red folder] (folder 6 of 6). (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous (folder 1 of 3). (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous (folder 2 of 3). (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous (folder 3 of 3). (Box 2)
- "Brazilian American" - clippings. (Box 3)
- Brazil. (Box 3)
- Correspondence. (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous, Inc. Correspondence. (Box 3)
- Notes. (Box 3)
- Writings. (Box 3)
- 8 unidentified folders. (Box 4)
- Let there be beer. (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 4)
- Zabaglione. (Box 4)
- 3 unidentified folders. (Box 5)
- Commonwealth College. (Box 5)
- 6 unidentified folders. (Box 6)
- 4 unidentified folders. (Box 7)
- Amazing Amazon/Joan d'Amazon. (Box 7)
- Biographical. (Box 7)
- Brazil. (Box 7)
- Brazil & Cookbooks. (Box 7)
- Gastronomy -- Cooking. (Box 7)
- Gastronomy -- Recipes. (Box 7)
- Gastronomy -- Recipes & Food. (Box 7)
- Tobacco. (Box 7)
- 4 unidentified folders. (Box 8)
- Gastronomy -- Recipes. (Box 8)
- Short Story: "A bird in the hand". (Box 8)
- Short Story: "Adventures of Hans Staden". (Box 8)
- Short Story: "Bible leaf". (Box 8)
- Short Story: "Duplix". (Box 8)
- Short Story: "Five thousand Dollars". (Box 8)
- Short Story: "Knights of the Garter". (Box 8)
- Short Story: "One good lick". (Box 8)
- Short Story: "Sanctuary beyond despair". (Box 8)
- Short Story: "Writings". (Box 8)
- 7 unidentified folders. (Box 9)
- Manuscript, Notes--Buy British, by Bob Brown. (Box 9)
- Short Story: "Blue-Beard's Book-case". (Box 9)
- Short Story: "From 10-Below to Dixie". (Box 9)
- Short Story: "Razors I've Escaped". (Box 9)
- Short Story: "Whispering Water". (Box 9)
- 6 unidentified folders. (Box 10)
- Scrapbook pages. (Box 10)
- The Amazon flows on. (Box 10)
- Writings. (Box 10)
- 8 unidentified folders. (Box 11)
- 4 unidentified folders. (Box 12)
- Commonwealth College. (Box 12)
- Short story fragments. (Box 12)
- USSR trip 1936. (Box 12)
- 4 unidentified folders. (Box 13)
- Poetry. (Box 13)
- "On Saint Teresa's Hill" - Short Story. (Box 14)
- 5 unidentified folders. (Box 14)
- Cooking Publications. (Box 14)
- Photographs of Brazil. (Box 14)
- Publishing efforts 1952-1953. (Box 14)
- The Adventures of Hans. (Box 14)
- 6 unidentified folders. (Box 15)
- Gastronomy -- Wine & Recipes. (Box 15)
- Published stories by Bob Brown. (Box 15)
- Published stories by various authors. (Box 15)
- 5 unidentified folders. (Box 16)
- Erotica. (Box 16)
- Gastronomy -- Cooking & Recipes. (Box 16)
- Printed stories by Bob Brown. (Box 16)
- 7 unidentified folders. (Box 17)
- Fate and the fifty. (Box 17)
- Miscellanious Photographs. (Box 17)
- Photographs of Brazil. (Box 17)
- Photographs of Mexico. (Box 17)
- 4 unidentified folders. (Box 18)
- A castle in Spain. (Box 18)
- A projection room project. (Box 18)
- At Madam Oliva's. (Box 18)
- Brown Family Robinson. (Box 18)
- City Falconer. (Box 18)
- Homes from Home. (Box 18)
- I'd Use Moth Balls. (Box 18)
- Poetry. (Box 18)
- Tillie Tiptoes. (Box 18)
- "Diet or Die" or "Lodging at the Sinza". (Box 19)
- 5 unidentified folders. (Box 19)
- Gastronomy -- Food. (Box 19)
- Pages from pulp fiction magazines. (Box 19)
- Printed stories by RCB. (Box 19)
- Shake a leg!. (Box 19)
- 6 unidentified folders. (Box 20)
- Fascism Afloat. (Box 20)
- Origin of the Numbers Game. (Box 20)
- 5 unidentified folders. (Box 21)
- A Castle in Spain. (Box 21)
- Correspondence with Allen Brown. (Box 21)
- Romance. (Box 21)
- Trade in S. American artifacts. (Box 21)
- Unidentified typescript, 85 p. (Box 21)
- 6 unidentified folders. (Box 22)
- Creation by John Szpila. (Box 22)
- Dick Dobbs Detective Weekly. (Box 22)
- Holy, Holy, Holy. (Box 22)
- Ship's Pools and Fools. (Box 22)
- The bloody beer battle. (Box 22)
- The Pigs in the Orchard by Cora L. Brown. (Box 22)
- Your Bawth is Ready, Sir!. (Box 22)
- 1 unidentified typescript, 1 incomplete p. 4 - 68. (Box 23)
- 7 unidentified folders. (Box 23)
- Brown Family Robinson. (Box 23)
- Down to Rio. (Box 23)
- Miniature Japanese Prints. (Box 23)
- The three-time crime. (Box 23)
- To lay our heads. (Box 23)
- We saw it coming. (Box 23)
- Wine & Food. (Box 23)
- 5 unidentified folders. (Box 24)
- Amazon Rubber. (Box 24)
- Gastronomy -- Food & Recipes. (Box 24)
- Gastronomy -- Recipes and Food. (Box 24)
- 6 unidentified folders. (Box 25)
- Abstract Art Today - Stuart Davis. (Box 25)
- Come hither, my sparrows!. (Box 25)
- Moscow Trip. (Box 25)
- Nuts to you. (Box 25)
- Pleasant Plains, New York City. (Box 25)
- Vote bait. (Box 25)
- 4 unidentified folders. (Box 26)
- Exodus. (Box 26)
- On barging about in a white suit. (Box 26)
- The Soot Box. (Box 26)
- 2 unidentified folders. (Box 27)
- Gastronomy -- Food and Drink. (Box 27)
- Gastronomy -- Recipes. (Box 27)
- 5 unidentified folders. (Box 28)
- Brazilian newspaper clippings. (Box 28)
- Fraternities. (Box 28)
- Guggenheim Fellowship Application. (Box 28)
- That Fraternal Feeling. (Box 28)
- Unidentified typescript, 145 p. (Box 28)
- 10% by James E. Sledge. (Box 29)
- 5 unidentified folders. (Box 29)
- Art and literature under capitalism. (Box 29)
- In the Devil's Dell. (Box 29)
- No coons look alike to me!. (Box 29)
- Studio - sitting. (Box 29)
- The bloody beer battle. (Box 29)
- 9 unidentified folders. (Box 30)
- At any L'Opera Tourist Agency. (Box 30)
- Lawrence Smith Correspondence. (Box 30)
- Maxim Gorky's Guerillas. (Box 30)
- 6 unidentified folders. (Box 31)
- Flared from Croze. (Box 31)
- Gastronomy -- Cheese. (Box 31)
- Gastronomy -- Cooking. (Box 31)
- Gastronomy -- Food and recipes. (Box 31)
- Our pin-up house on Tumble Mountain. (Box 31)
- 11 unidentified folders. (Box 32)
- All ashore that's goin' ashore. (Box 32)
- An arrowheads a poem. (Box 32)
- Autobiographical. (Box 32)
- Brazil writings. (Box 32)
- Bringing 'Em Back Alive. (Box 32)
- Chess among the artists. (Box 32)
- Forty years a cook's conductor. (Box 32)
- Gastronomy -- Recipes. (Box 32)
- Midnight by Rose Brown. (Box 32)
- Reading Machine--correspondence (includes mention of Gertrude Stein); various notes. (Box 32)
- Reading Machine--correspondence, clippings. (Box 32)
- Reading Machine--Notes, Correspondence, Clippings. (Box 32)
- Reading Machine--Review by Kate Boyle in CONTEMPO. (Box 32)
- Reading Machine--Review of Readies Anthology. (Box 32)
- The autobiography of art. (Box 32)
- Trip to Soviet Union. (Box 32)
- What the Soviet Union means to humanity. (Box 32)
- 5 unidentified folders. (Box 33)
- Brazilian American v. 1, #11, 12, 14-20. (Box 33)
- Cora's [?] Journal. (Box 33)
- Gastronomy -- Bible Cook Book by Marian Maeve O'Brien. (Box 33)
- 9 unidentified folders. (Box 34)
- A long-shot at Longchamp. (Box 34)
- Easy come, not so easy to go!. (Box 34)
- Gastronomy -- South American Cookbook Scrapbook. (Box 34)
- Gypsy's Revenge. (Box 34)
- It happened aboard the "Matinee boat". (Box 34)
- Marathon Marriage. (Box 34)
- Painting the Orchid. (Box 34)
- Silver Ball at Webster Hall. (Box 34)
- Sir Isaac to the rescue. (Box 34)
- The Golden Whale. (Box 34)
- The Wooden-Headed Nutmeg. (Box 34)
- Wall Street and Wobblies. (Box 34)
- 6 unidentified folders. (Box 35)
- Fellow countryman come to see us. (Box 35)
- 8 unidentified folders. (Box 36)
- Book selling. (Box 36)
- English as he is spoken. (Box 36)
- My happy valley. (Box 36)
- Poetry. (Box 36)
- The finger of God. (Box 36)
- 12 unidentified folders. (Box 37)
- Chapter VIII Tyrol and the Tyrolese. (Box 37)
- Gemutlichkeit. (Box 37)
- How to know good beer. (Box 37)
- Radish Potatoes and the Terrifying Pretzel Sword. (Box 37)
- Shoot if you must. (Box 37)
- Take the beer cure. (Box 37)
- The Day Before. (Box 37)
- 6 unidentified folders. (Box 38)
- Book orders. (Box 38)
- Ernesto Burrows correspondence. (Box 38)
- In the Devel's Dell. (Box 38)
- Limericks. (Box 38)
- Notes on Petropolis. (Box 38)
- Our house in the jungle. (Box 38)
- The City of Peter. (Box 38)
- 9 unidentified folders. (Box 39)
- Book orders. (Box 39)
- Brown Family Robinson. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Florida Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Georgia Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Indiana Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Iowa Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Kansas Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Kentucky Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Louisiana Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Maine Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Maryland Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- New Mexico Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- North Carolina Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- North Dakota Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Ohio Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Oregon Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Pennsylvania Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Rhode Island Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- South Carolina Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- South Dakota Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Southern Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Tennessee Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Texas Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Vermont Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Virginia Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Washington Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Washington D.C. Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- West Virginia Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Wisconsin Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Gastronomy -- Wyoming Cook Books. (Box 39)
- Inside Information. (Box 39)
- Letters of Condolence on Bob Brown's death. (Box 39)
- Puerto Rican Rum. (Box 39)
- Sporting Books. (Box 39)
- 5 unidentified folders. (Box 40)
- Charles Duff correspondence. (Box 40)
- Just a poor fish. (Box 40)
- Letter from Oaxaca. (Box 40)
- Mad Mary. (Box 40)
- Outline for a novel. (Box 40)
- The news clipping by Cora Brown. (Box 40)
- The oil of change. (Box 40)
- Various pages from Punch Magazine. (Box 40)
- "Land and people of Brazil" corrections. (Box 41)
- 6 unidentified folders. (Box 41)
- Asthma. (Box 41)
- Aviation. (Box 41)
- Book trade. (Box 41)
- Book trade correspondence. (Box 41)
- Gastronomy -- Connecticut cook book lists. (Box 41)
- Gastronomy -- Delaware cook books. (Box 41)
- Gastronomy -- Food and cooking. (Box 41)
- Gastronomy -- South American recipes. (Box 41)
- Lists of books for sale by Bob Brown. (Box 41)
- O.R. Cleveland correspondence. (Box 41)
- Texas almanac fragment. (Box 41)
- [A Brazilian's trip to New York]. (Box 42)
- [Unidentified story]. (Box 42)
- 1910 letter from Rose Brown to Bob Brown. (Box 42)
- 5 unidentified folders. (Box 42)
- A delicatessen dialogue. (Box 42)
- Art and Terese. (Box 42)
- Aviation notebook. (Box 42)
- Gastronomy -- Cooking tips. (Box 42)
- Gastronomy -- Cooking with a spike. (Box 42)
- Gastronomy -- Drinks. (Box 42)
- Gastronomy -- Potato book. (Box 42)
- Gastronomy -- What's your recipe?. (Box 42)
- Hay, but no horse. (Box 42)
- Horse butcher. (Box 42)
- Just a matter of taste. (Box 42)
- Mc Sorley's. (Box 42)
- My Manhattan. (Box 42)
- The bishop's hip bath by Rose Brown. (Box 42)
- The burglary. (Box 42)
- 9 unidentified folders. (Box 43)
- Punch magazine - various pages. (Box 43)
- The Rah-Rah Boys on the rah-de-o. (Box 43)
- 9 unidentified folders. (Box 44)
- Bob Brown CV. (Box 44)
- Cheese typescript - various pages (folder 1 of 2). (Box 44)
- Cheese typescript - various pages (folder 2 of 2). (Box 44)
- Correspondence. (Box 44)
- In the Ganges River by Cora Brown. (Box 44)
- O, give me a ship with a sail. (Box 44)
- On Saint Teresa's hill. (Box 44)
- Ozark Jack - various pages. (Box 44)
- Studio sittings. (Box 44)
- The monkey and the mango. (Box 44)
- Vol. 1. No. 1. (Box 44)
- Welcome to Coral Beaches. (Box 44)
- 9 unidentified folders. (Box 45)
- Gastronomy -- Food and recipes (folder 1 of 2). (Box 45)
- Gastronomy -- Food and recipes (folder 2 of 2). (Box 45)
- Gastronomy -- Wine. (Box 45)
- Old dynamite. (Box 45)
- Rose Brown's Brazilian identity card. (Box 45)
- The Jones beach. (Box 45)
- What to do with due bills. (Box 45)
- 2 unidentified folders. (Box 46)
- Correspondence. (Box 46)
- Downstream people. (Box 46)
- Fishing. (Box 46)
- How it's done in Banff. (Box 46)
- Lake Garda. (Box 46)
- Oh baby!. (Box 46)
- Petropolis. (Box 46)
- Punch magazine - various pages. (Box 46)
- Scrapbook of writings by Bob Brown. (Box 46)
- Ship pools and fools. (Box 46)
- Streets that sing. (Box 46)
- The first time we saw Rio. (Box 46)
- The pride of Princess Maginel. (Box 46)
- Tickets for two!. (Box 46)
- Traitors on trial. (Box 46)
- With the educated mice in the Palais Royal by Rose Brown. (Box 46)
- Writings on travels in Peru. (Box 46)
- 7 unidentified folders. (Box 47)
- Decline Spaghetti. (Box 47)
- Gastronomy -- Complete book of Cheese - correspondence with Clifton Fadiman. (Box 47)
- Gastronomy -- Complete book of cheese - notes (folder 1 of 3). (Box 47)
- Gastronomy -- Complete book of cheese - notes (folder 2 of 3). (Box 47)
- Gastronomy -- Complete book of cheese - notes (folder 3 of 3). (Box 47)
- On the sidewalks of New York. (Box 47)
- Sidewalk contrasts. (Box 47)
- South American travel journal. (Box 47)
- 9 unidentified folders. (Box 48)
- A crumb of it. (Box 48)
- Can we learn about sex from the salmon, or vice versa. (Box 48)
- Correspondence. (Box 48)
- Federal Register - National Archives. (Box 48)
- Frederick Philip Stieff correspondence. (Box 48)
- Gastronomy -- Cheese book typescript - various pages. (Box 48)
- Gastronomy -- South American cookbook recipes. (Box 48)
- Holding Brenner Pass. (Box 48)
- Punch magazine - various pages. (Box 48)
- The fondue. (Box 48)
- "Amazing Amazon". Collection of Brazilian indian artifacts. (Box 49)
- 4 unidentified folders. (Box 49)
- America cooks - scrapbook. (Box 49)
- Food. (Box 49)
- Food, cooking and recipes (folder 1 of 3). (Box 49)
- Food, cooking and recipes (folder 2 of 3). (Box 49)
- Food, cooking and recipes (folder 3 of 3). (Box 49)
- 8 unidentified folders. (Box 50)
- Century Magazine. (Box 50)
- Punch. (Box 50)
- 5 unidentified folders. (Box 51)
- Almost geometrical progression. (Box 51)
- American folk song in Paris. (Box 51)
- Drinks. (Box 51)
- Recipes. (Box 51)
- Recipes and cooking (folder 1 of 2). (Box 51)
- Recipes and cooking (folder 2 of 2). (Box 51)
- Senor Murph sells us a mine. (Box 51)
- Sheila. (Box 51)
- The winter of our content. (Box 51)
- 4 unidentified folders. (Box 52)
- Bee-lieve it or not!. (Box 52)
- Bob Brown letters to "Red". (Box 52)
- Bob Brown letters to mother. (Box 52)
- Brown's Collegiate Pictionary. (Box 52)
- C. Lanye correspondence. (Box 52)
- Cooking and food. (Box 52)
- Cooking with a flair. Book proposal. (Box 52)
- Do you smorg? Lobster unlimited. (Box 52)
- Food. (Box 52)
- Honey. (Box 52)
- Pets cook book (folder 1 of 2). (Box 52)
- Pets cook book (folder 2 of 2). (Box 52)
- Poetry. (Box 52)
- Sundowner parties. (Box 52)
- Synopsis for a story about honey. (Box 52)
- When Tarzan entertains. (Box 52)
- "Amazing Amazon" scrapbook. (Box 53)
- 3 unidentified folders. (Box 53)
- American Museum of Natural History, Central Park. 2 fold-out photograph books. (Box 53)
- Brazil. (Box 53)
- Louisiana oil well deeds. (Box 53)
- Miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 53)
- Moscow Theater Festival. (Box 53)
- South American cook book recipes. (Box 53)
- Starving Russia by Rose and Bob Brown. (Box 53)
- Travels in the USSR. (Box 53)
- Unclub legalized thugs. (Box 53)
- USSR. (Box 53)
- 3 unidentified folders. (Box 54)
- A Spanish cockfight. (Box 54)
- Brotherhoods - draft (folder 1 of 2). (Box 54)
- Brotherhoods - draft (folder 2 of 2). (Box 54)
- Captain of the ship of fools. (Box 54)
- Cheese book - copyright dispute. (Box 54)
- Christmas cards. (Box 54)
- Come to Coral Beeches!. (Box 54)
- Gran Circo Bufalo Bill. (Box 54)
- Hoarding. (Box 54)
- Material for the complete book of cheese. (Box 54)
- Maxim Gorky's guerillas. (Box 54)
- Moscow 1935. Day & Night. A super mass novel. (Box 54)
- Moscow News. (Box 54)
- New soviet words. (Box 54)
- Our alarming expatriates. (Box 54)
- Overseas blues. (Box 54)
- Postcards. (Box 54)
- Sizzling rabbits. (Box 54)
- Slippers, can you spare a drum-stick?. (Box 54)
- So this is Moscow!. (Box 54)
- The complete book of cheese - reviews and notices. (Box 54)
- The last of the Rasputins. (Box 54)
- Traitors on trial. (Box 54)
- Travels on the Amazon in Brazil and Peru. (Box 54)
- USSR trip and related material. (Box 54)
- 3 unidentified folders. (Box 55)
- Books and bookdealers (folder 1 of 4). (Box 55)
- Books and bookdealers (folder 2 of 4). (Box 55)
- Books and bookdealers (folder 3 of 4). (Box 55)
- Books and bookdealers (folder 4 of 4). (Box 55)
- Brazilian history. (Box 55)
- Picketing. (Box 55)
- "1928". (Box 56)
- "1929". (Box 56)
- "Brazilian American" - various pages. (Box 56)
- 6 unidentified folders. (Box 56)
- A couple of Carmens & good manners. (Box 56)
- Argentine one night stand. (Box 56)
- At Don Jose's (2 copies). (Box 56)
- At home in the Impeho by Rose and Bob Brown. (Box 56)
- Club me no clubs. (Box 56)
- Cooking, eating and drinking outdoors by Bob brown and Charles Flato - outline. (Box 56)
- Correspondence. (Box 56)
- Fascism afloat by Rose and Bob Brown. (Box 56)
- Hochzeit with German cowboys (incomplete). (Box 56)
- Letters from Oaxaca (Good neighbour letters from Mexico). (Box 56)
- Lists of books for sale by Bob Brown Books. (Box 56)
- Shake a leg!. (Box 56)
- The little mother in gray. (Box 56)
- The red skins of Munich (4+ copies). (Box 56)
- "Old letters". (Box 57)
- 4 unidentified folders. (Box 57)
- Carlton Brown (Bob's son). (Box 57)
- Cheese and recipes. (Box 57)
- Correspondence. (Box 57)
- Drinks and alcohol. (Box 57)
- Lists of books for sale by Bob Brown Books. (Box 57)
- Part of typescript on travels in South America. (Box 57)
- Santarem, Brazil, correspondence. (Box 57)
- 8 unidentified folders. (Box 58)
- A crumb of it. (Box 58)
- Cookbooks. (Box 58)
- Cookbooks and recipes (folder 1 of 2). (Box 58)
- Cookbooks and recipes (folder 2 of 2). (Box 58)
- Cooking and recipes. (Box 58)
- Frank Gray Griswold. (Box 58)
- My first writing friends. (Box 58)
- Setting out the garlic sets. (Box 58)
- The bone book. (Box 58)
- 8 unidentified folders. (Box 59)
- Address book. (Box 59)
- From sow bugs to sea cows. (Box 59)
- Funny little faces in the sand by Rose and Bob Brown. (Box 59)
- Good neighbor galleries. (Box 59)
- Good neighbor treasure hunt. (Box 59)
- Herbs. (Box 59)
- Herbs, spices and flavors. (Box 59)
- Home town. (Box 59)
- Incomplete article on Peru. (Box 59)
- Inter-American Museum Association. (Box 59)
- Mystery chef. (Box 59)
- Pensao Brazil. (Box 59)
- Salads and herbs by Cora, Rose and Bob Brown - loose pages from the book. (Box 59)
- Solomon the third. (Box 59)
- Terse verse. (Box 59)
- USSR pictures and paintings. (Box 59)
- 7 unidentified folders. (Box 60)
- Brazilian heroes by Rose Brown. (Box 60)
- Homes from home by Rose and Bob Brown (2 copies). (Box 60)
- Latin American travel book - various chapters and pages. (Box 60)
- My happy view valley - rough draft of book by Rose Brown. (Box 60)
- Quack! Quack!. (Box 60)